Finding Aid for Irma Bielenberg papers, 1893-1974
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Irma Bielenberg papers 1893-1974
Bielenberg, Irma, 1891-1981.
2 linear feet
8573 Aa 2
Teacher and Methodist missionary to India, 1924-1927.Correspondence and printed material concerning her work in India, college notebooks and papers from Detroit Teachers College; thesis "Economic Detroit--1860-1870"; family letters, many in Swedish, relating in part to Michigan's Upper Peninsula at the end of the nineteenth century; and miscellaneous journals, papers, and photographs.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Bielenberg's niece, Mrs. Marlene Barr (Donor no. 6513 ), and came to the library in 1981-1982 and 1991.
No further additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Irma C. Bielenberg was a teacher and a Methodist missionary to India, 1924-1927.
The papers of Irma Bielenberg cover the period of 1893 to 1974 and include correspondence and printed material concerning her work in India, college notebooks and papers from Detroit Teachers College, a thesis entitled, "Economic Detroit--1860-1870," travel diaries, photographs from India and from South America, and family letters (many in Swedish) relating to life in the Upper Peninsula of Michigan at the end of the nineteenth century.
Subjects:
Bielenberg, Irma C. (Irma Christina), 1891-; Detroit (Mich.)--History.; Upper Peninsula (Mich.); Missionaries--India.; Methodist Episcopal Church--Missions--India.; India.; Swedish Americans--Michigan.; Women college students--Michigan--Detroit.; Women missionaries--India.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Bielenberg, Irma C. (Irma Christina), 1891-; Clothing and dress.; India.; Missionaries--India.; South America.; Tourism; Transportation--India.; Women.; Methodist Episcopal Church--Missions--India.
Genre Terms:
Diaries.; Photographs.
- Biographical Material
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
- Correspondence, 1847-1974
  - Miscellaneous, undated, ca. 1924-1960 (Box 1)
  - 1847-1923 (Box 1)
  - 1924 (Box 1)
  - January-June, 1925 (Box 1)
  - July 1925-1926 (Box 1)
  - January-June 1927 (Box 1)
  - July-December 1927 (Box 1)
  - January-June 1928 (Box 1)
  - July-December 1928 (Box 1)
  - 1929 (Box 1)
  - 1930-1931 (Box 1)
  - 1932-1935 (Box 1)
  - 1936-1939 (Box 1)
  - 1940-1942 (Box 1)
  - 1943-1950 (Box 1)
  - 1951-1974 (Box 1)
- Family Correspondence, 1893-1968
  - 1893-1920 (Box 1)
  - 1923-1925 (Box 1)
  - 1926 (Box 1)
  - 1927-1932 (Box 1)
  - 1933 (Box 1)
  - 1934-1937 (Box 1)
  - 1938-1948 (Box 1)
  - 1950-1968 (Box 1)
- Missionary Newsletters, 1925-1964
  - 1925-1949 (Box 1)
  - 1953-1964 (Box 1)
- College Notebooks and Exams
  - Undated, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - ca. 1930-1931 (Box 1)
  - "Economic Detroit--1860-1870." Wayne University (term paper, 1931 thesis, 1939) (Box 1)
- Writings and notebooks, undated
  - Religion (Box 2)
  - India (Box 2)
- Travel journals, 1924-1948
  - India, 1924-1927, 2 volumes (Box 2)
  - Europe, 1930 (Box 2)
  - Alaska, 1934 (Box 2)
  - South America, 1935 (Box 2)
  - Central and South America, 1948 (Box 2)
- Printed Material and miscellaneous
  - Miscellaneous and undated (Box 2)
  - 1924-1925 (Box 2)
  - 1926-1930 (Box 2)
  - 1931-1965 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous (non-printed), 3 folders (Box 2)
- Photographs
  - Portraits and personal photos (Box 2)
  - Foreign lands and missionaries (Box 2)
  - Students and friends, 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 2)